Expanding is the task of taking a shorter piece of text
such as a set of instructions or a list of topics
and having the large language model generate a longer piece of text
such as an email or an essay about some topic
There are some great uses of this
such as if you use a large language model as a brainstorming partner
But I just also want to acknowledge that there's
some problematic use cases of this
such as if someone were to use it to generate a large amount of spam
So when you use these capabilities of a large language model
please use it only in a responsible way and in a way that helps people
In this video, we'll go through an example of how you can use
a language model to generate a personalized email based on some information
The email is kind of self-proclaimed to be from an AI bot
which as Andrew mentioned, is very important
We're also going to use another one of
the model's input parameters called temperature
and this allows you to vary the degree of
exploration and variety in the model's responses
So let's get into it
So before we get started
we're going to do the usual setup
So set up the OpenAI Python package
and then also define our helper function, get_completion
Now we're going to write a custom email response to a customer review
So given a customer review and the sentiment
we're going to generate a custom response
Now we're going to use the language model to generate
a custom email to a customer based on a customer review
and the sentiment of the review
So we've already extracted the sentiment
using the kind of prompts that we saw in the inferring video
and then this is the customer review for a blender
Now we're going to customize the reply based on the sentiment
So here the instruction is
you are a customer service AI assistant
Your task is to send an email reply to a valued customer
Given the customer email delimited by three backticks
generate a reply to thank the customer for their review
If the sentiment is positive or neutral
thank them for their review
If the sentiment is negative
apologize and suggest that they can reach out to customer service
Make sure to use specific details from the review
write in a concise and professional tone
and sign the email as AI customer agent
When you're using a language model
to generate text that you're going to show to a user
it's very important to have this kind of transparency
and let the user know that the text they're seeing was generated by AI
Then we'll just input the customer review and the review sentiment
Also note that this part isn't necessarily important
because we could actually use this prompt to also extract the review sentiment
and then in a follow-up step, write the email
But just for the sake of the example
well, we've already extracted the sentiment from the review
So here we have a response to the customer
It addresses details that the customer mentioned in their review
and as we instructed
suggest that they reach out to customer service
because this is just an AI customer service agent
Next, we're going to use a parameter of the language model called temperature
that will allow us to change the variety of the model's responses
So you can think of temperature as
the degree of exploration or randomness of the model
So for this particular phrase
my favorite food is
the most likely next word that the model predicts is pizza
and the next two most likely
it suggests are sushi and tacos
So at a temperature of zero
the model will always choose the most likely next word
which in this case is pizza
and at a higher temperature
it will also choose one of the less likely words
and at an even higher temperature
it might even choose tacos
which only has a five percent chance of being chosen
You can imagine that as the model continues this final response
so my favorite food is pizza
and it continues to generate more words
this response will diverge from the first response
which is my favorite food is tacos
So as the model continues
these two responses will become more and more different
In general, when building applications where you want
a predictable response
I would recommend using temperature zero
Throughout all of these videos
we've been using temperature zero
and I think that if you're trying to build a system that
is reliable and predictable, you should go with this
If you're trying to use the model in a more creative way
where you might want a wider variety of different outputs
you might want to use a higher temperature
So now let's take this same prompt that we just used
and let's try generating an e-mail
but let's use a higher temperature
So in our get_completion function that we've been using throughout the videos
we have specified a model and then also a temperature
but we've set them to default
So now let's try varying the temperature
So we use the prompt
and then let's try temperature=0.7
And so with temperature=0
every time you execute the same prompt
you should expect the same completion
whereas with temperature 0.7
you'll get a different output every time
So here we have our e-mail
and as you can see, it's different to the e-mail
that we received previously
And let's just execute it again to show that we'll get a different e-mail again
And here we have another different e-mail
So I recommend that you play around with temperature yourself
Maybe you could pause the video now and try this prompt
with a variety of different temperatures
just to see how the outputs vary
So to summarize, at higher temperatures
the outputs from the model are kind of more random
You can almost think of it as that at higher temperatures
the assistant is more distractible
but maybe more creative
In the next video, we're going to talk more about
the chat completions endpoint format
and how you can create a custom chatbot using this format