When I've been building applications with large language models
I don't think I've ever come to the prompt that I ended up
using in the final application on my first attempt
And this isn't what matters
As long as you have a good process to iteratively make your prompt better
then you'll be able to come to something that
works well for the task you want to achieve
You may have heard me say that when I train a machine learning model
it almost never works the first time
In fact, I'm very surprised that the first model I trained works
I think we're prompting, the odds of it working the first time is maybe a little bit
higher but as she's saying
doesn't matter if the first prompt works
what matters most is the process for getting to prompts that works for your application
So with that, let's jump into the code and let me show you
some frameworks to think about how to iteratively develop a prompt
All right. So if you've taken a machine learning class with me
before you may have seen me use a diagram saying that with machine learning development
you often have an idea and then implement it
So write the code, get the data
train your model and that gives you an experimental result
And you can then look at that output
maybe do error analysis
figure out where it's working or not working
and then maybe even change your idea of
exactly what problem you want to solve or how to approach it
And then change implementation and run
another experiment and so on and iterate over and
over to get to an effective machine learning model
If you're not familiar with machine learning
haven't seen this diagram before, don't worry about it
Not that important for the rest of this presentation
But when you are writing prompts to develop an application using an LLM
the process can be quite similar
where you have an idea for what you want to do
the task you want to complete
and you can then take a first attempt at writing
a prompt that hopefully is clear and specific
and maybe if appropriate
gives the system time to think
And then you can run it and see what result you get
And if it doesn't work well enough the first time
then the iterative process of figuring out why the instructions
for example, were not clear enough or why it
didn't give the algorithm enough time to think
allows you to refine the idea
refine the prompt, and so on
and to go around this loop multiple times
until you end up with a prompt that works for your application
This too is why I personally have not paid as much attention to
the Internet articles that say 30 perfect prompts because I think
there probably isn't a perfect prompt for everything under the sun
It's more important that you have a process for
developing a good prompt for your specific application
So let's look at an example together in code
I have here the starter code that you saw in
the previous videos have been import openai and port is
Here we get the OpenAI API key
and this is the same helper function that you saw as last time
And I'm going to use as the running example in this video
the task of summarizing a fact sheet for a chair
So let me just paste that in here
and feel free to pause the video and read
this more carefully in the notebook on the left if you want
But here's a fact sheet for a chair with a description saying it's part of
a beautiful family of mid-century inspired and so on
talks about the construction
has the dimensions, options for the chair
materials, and so on. It comes from Italy
So let's say you want to take this fact sheet and help
a marketing team write a description for an online retail website
Let me just quickly run these three
and then we'll come up with a prompt as follows
I'll just paste this in
So my prompt here says
your task is to help a marketing team create
a description for a retail website or product based on a techno fact sheet
write a product description, and so on
So this is my first attempt to explain the task to the large language model
So let me hit Shift Enter
and this takes a few seconds to run
and we get this result
It looks like it's done a nice job writing a description
introducing a stunning mid-century inspired office chair
perfect addition, and so on
But when I look at this, I go
boy, this is really long
It's done a nice job doing exactly what I asked it to
which is start from the technical fact sheet and write a product description
But when I look at this, I go
this is long, maybe we want it to be a little bit shorter
So I had an idea
I wrote a prompt, got a result
I'm not that happy with it because it's too long
So I will then clarify my prompt
um, and say, use at most 50 words to try to give
better guidance on the desired length of this and let's run it again
Okay. This actually looks like a much nicer short description of, uh
the product introducing a mid-century inspired office chair, and so on
5-wheel base, yeah
both stylish and practical
Not bad. Um, and let me double-check the length that this is
So I'm going to take the response, split it
according to where the space is
and then, you know, print out the length
So it's 52 words
It's actually not bad
Um, large language models are okay
but not that great at following instructions about a very precise word count
But this is actually not bad
Sometimes it will print out something with 60 or 65 and so on words
but it's kind of within reason
Some of the things you could try to do would be
um, to say, use at most three sentences
Let me run that again
But these are different ways to tell
the large language model what's the length of the output that you want
So this is 1, 2, 3
I count three sentences
It looks like I did a pretty good job
Um, and then I've also seen people sometimes do things like
uh, I don't know, use at most 280 characters
Large language models, because of the way they interpret text
using something called a tokenizer
which I won't talk about
But, um, they tend to be so-so at counting characters
But let's see, 281 characters
It's actually surprisingly close
Usually a large language model is- doesn't get it quite this close
But these are different ways
They can play with to try to control the length of the output that you get
But let me just switch it back to use at most 50 words
And there's that result that we had just now
As we continue to refine this text for our websites
we might decide that, boy
this website isn't selling direct to consumers
is actually intended to sell furniture to
furniture retailers that would be more interested in
the technical details of the chair and the materials of the chair
In that case, you can take this prompt and say
I want to modify this prompt to get it to be more precise about the technical details
So let me keep on modifying this prompt
And I'm going to say, this description is intended for furniture retailers
so should be technical and focus on materials
products and constructed from
Let's run that
And let's see
Not bad, says, you know
coated aluminum base and pneumatic chair, high quality materials
So by changing the prompt
you can get it to focus more on specific characters
on specific characteristics you wanted to
And when I look at this
I might decide at the end of the description
I also wanted to include the product IDs
So the two offerings of this chair
SWC 110, SWC 100
So maybe I can further improve this prompt
And to get it to give me the product IDs
I can add this instruction at the end of the description
include every seven character product ID in the technical specification
And let's run it and see what happens
And so it says, introduce your administration's file office chair
shell colors, talks about plastic coating, aluminum base
practical, some options
talks about the two product IDs
So this looks pretty good
And what you've just seen is a short example of the iterative
prompt development that many developers will go through
And I think a guideline is
in the last video, you saw Isa share a number of best practices
And so what I usually do is keep best practices like that in mind
be clear and specific, and if necessary
give the model time to think
With those in mind, it's worthwhile to often take a first attempt at writing a prompt
see what happens, and then go from there to iteratively refine the prompt to get
closer and closer to the results that you need
And so a lot of the successful prompts that you may see used in various programs
was arrived at at an iterative process like this
Just for fun, let me show you an example of a even more complex prompt that might
give you a sense of what ChatGPT can do
which is I've just added a few extra instructions here
After the description, include a table that gives the product dimensions
and then, you know, format everything as HTML
So let's run that
And in practice, you would end up with a prompt like this
really only after multiple iterations
I don't think I know anyone that would write this exact prompt the first time
they were trying to get the system to process a fact sheet
And so this actually outputs a bunch of HTML
Let's display the HTML to see if this is even valid HTML and see if this works
And I don't actually know it's going to work, but let's see
Oh, cool. All right
Looks like it rendered
So it has this really nice looking description of a chair
construction, materials, product dimensions
Oh, it looks like I left out the use at most 50 words instruction
So this is a little bit long, but if you want that, you know
you can even feel free to pause the video
tell it to be more succinct and regenerate this and see what results you get
So I hope you take away from this video that
prompt development is an iterative process
Try something, see how it does not yet fulfill exactly what you want
and then think about how to clarify your instructions
or in some cases, think about how to give it more space to think
to get it closer to delivering the results that you want
And I think the key to being an effective prompt engineer
isn't so much about knowing the perfect prompt
it's about having a good process to develop
prompts that are effective for your application
And in this video, I illustrated developing a prompt using just one example
For more sophisticated applications
sometimes you will have multiple examples
say a list of 10 or even 50 or 100 fact sheets
and iteratively develop a prompt and evaluate it against a large set of cases
But for the early development of most applications
I see many people developing it sort of the way I am with just one example
But then for more mature applications
sometimes it could be useful to evaluate prompts against a larger set of examples
such as to test different prompts on dozens of fact sheets to see
how is average or worst case performances on multiple fact sheets
But usually, you end up doing that only when an application is more mature
and you have to have those metrics to drive
that incremental last few steps of prompt improvement
So with that, please do play with
the Jupyter Code notebook examples and try out
different variations and see what results you get
And when you're done, let's go on to the next video
where we'll talk about one very common use of
large language models in software applications
which is to summarize text
So when you're ready, let's go on to the next video