Congratulations on making it to the end of this short course
In summary, in this short course
you've learned about two key principles for prompting
right clearance for specific instructions and when it's appropriate
give the model time to think
You also learned about iterative prompt development and how
having a process to get to the prompt is right for your application is key
And we went through a few capabilities of
large language models that are useful for many applications
specifically summarizing, inferring, transforming, and expanding
And you also saw how to build a custom chatbot
That was a lot that you learned in just one short course
and I hope you enjoyed going through these materials
We hope you'll come up with some ideas for
applications that you can build yourself now
And please go try this out and let us know what you come up with
No application is too small
It's fine to start with something that's kind of
a very small project with maybe a little bit of utility
or maybe it's not even useful at all
It's just something fun
Yeah. And I find playing with these models actually really fun
So go play with it
Yeah, I agree. It's a good
a good weekend activity, speaking from experience
And just, you know
please use the learnings from your first project to build a better second project
and you know, maybe even a better third project, so on
That's kind of how I have kind of grown over time using these models myself as well
Or if you have an idea for a bigger project already, just, just go for it
And, you know, as a reminder
these kind of large language models are a very powerful technology
So it kind of goes without saying that we ask you to use them responsibly
and please only build things that will have a positive impact
Yeah, fully agree. I think in this age
people that build AI systems can have a huge impact on others
So it's more important than ever that all of us only use these tools responsibly
And I think building large language model-based applications
is just a very exciting and growing field right now
And now that you've finished this course
I think you now have a wealth of knowledge to let
you build things that few people today know how to
So I hope you also help us to spread the word and encourage others to take this course too
In closing, I hope you had fun doing this course
and I want to thank you for finishing this course
and both Isa and I look forward to hearing about the amazing things that you've built