There's so much text in today's world, pretty much none of us have enough time to read all
the things we wish we had time to
So one of the most exciting applications I've seen of large language models is to use it
to summarize text
And this is something that I'm seeing multiple teams build into multiple software applications
You can do this in the ChatGPT web interface
I do this all the time to summarize articles so I can just kind of read the content of
many more articles than I previously could
And if you want to do this more programmatically, you'll see how to in this lesson
So that's let's dig into the code to see how you could use this yourself to summarize text
So let's start off with the same starter code as you saw before of import openai, load the
API key and here's that get_completion helper function
I'm going to use as the running example, the task of summarizing this product review
Got this panda plush toy for my daughter's birthday
and so on and so on
If you're building an e commerce website, and there's just a large volume of reviews
having a tool to summarize the lengthy reviews could give you a way to very quickly glance
over more reviews to get a better sense of what all your customers are thinking
So here's a prompt for generating a summary
Your task is generate a short summary of a product review from e commerce website, summarize
review below, and so on, in at most 30 words
And so this is soft and cute panda plush toy loved by daughter, but small for the price
arrived early
Not bad
It's a pretty good summary
And as you saw in the previous video, you can also play with things like controlling
the character count or the number of sentences to affect the length of this summary
Now sometimes when creating a summary, if you have a very specific purpose in mind for
the summary, for example, if you want to give feedback to the shipping department, you can
also modify the prompt to reflect that so that they can generate a summary that is more
applicable to one particular group in your business
So for example, if I add to give feedback to the shipping department, let's say I change
this to start to focus on any aspects that mention shipping and delivery of the product
And if I run this, then again, you get a summary, but instead of starting off with soft and
cute panda plush toy, it now focuses on the fact that it arrived a day earlier than expected
And then it still has, you know, other details
Or as another example, if we aren't trying to give feedback to the shipping department
but let's say we want to give feedback to the pricing department
So the pricing department is responsible for determining the price of the product
And I'm going to tell it to focus on any aspects that are relevant to the price and perceived
value
Then this generates a different summary that it says
maybe the price may be too high for a size
Now in the summaries that I've generated for the shipping department or the pricing department
it focuses a bit more on information relevant to those specific departments
And in fact, feel free to pause the video now and maybe ask it to generate information
for the product department responsible for the customer experience of the product or
for something else that you think might be interesting to an e-commerce site
But in these summaries, even though it generated the information relevant to shipping, it had
some other information too, which you could decide may or may not be helpful
So depending on how you want to summarize it, you can also ask it to extract information
rather than summarize it
So here's a prompt that says you're tasked to extract relevant information to give feedback
to the shipping department
And now it just says, product arrived a day earlier than expected without all of the other
information, which was also helpful in a general summary, but less specific to the shipping
department if all it wants to know is what happened with the shipping
Lastly, let me just share with you a concrete example for how to use this in a workflow
to help summarize multiple reviews to make them easier to read
So here are a few reviews
This is kind of long, but here's a second review for a standing lamp
need a lamp on a bedroom
Here's a third review for an electric toothbrush
My dental hygienist recommended
Kind of a long review about the electric toothbrush
This is a review for a blender when it said, so said 17 piece system on seasonal sale and
so on and so on
This is actually a lot of text
If you want, feel free to pause the video and read through all this text
But what if you want to know what these reviewers wrote without having to stop and read all
this in detail?
So I'm going to set review_1 to be just the product review that we had up there
I'm going to put all of these reviews into a list
And now if I implement a for loop over the reviews
So here's my prompt and here I've asked it to summarize it in at most 20 words
Then let's have it get the response and print it out
And let's run that
And it prints out the first review is that PandaToy review, summary review of the lamp
summary review of the toothbrush, and then the blender
And so if you have a website where you have hundreds of reviews, you can imagine how you
might use this to build a dashboard, to take huge numbers of reviews, generate short summaries
of them so that you or someone else can browse the reviews much more quickly
And then if they wish, maybe click in to see the original longer review
And this can help you efficiently get a better sense of what all of your customers are thinking
All right, so that's it for summarizing
And I hope that you can picture if you have any applications with many pieces of text
how you can use prompts like these to summarize them to help people quickly get a sense of
what's in the text, the many pieces of text, and perhaps optionally dig in more
if they wish
In the next video, we'll look at another capability of large language models, which is to make
inferences using text
For example, what if you had, again, product reviews, and you wanted to very quickly get
a sense of which product reviews have a positive or a negative sentiment?
Let's take a look at how to do that in the next video